Finding Aid for Frank Murphy Papers, 1908-1949
Bentley Historical Library
- Miscellaneous
  - Check stubs and bank statements (Box 84)
  - Appointments to Attorney General
    - January 2, 1939 (Folder Ac)
    - January 20, 1939 (Folder Ac)
    - Campaign poster re Mackinac Bridge, November 4, 1938 (Folder Ac)
  - Invitations, 1908-1949; undated (Box 85)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 86)
  - Memorandum to Attorney General Frank Murphy from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1939 (Box 87)
  - Memorandum to Attorney General Frank Murphy from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1939 (Box 88)
    (continued)
  - Memorandum to Attorney General Frank Murphy from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1939 (Box 89)
  - Appointment Calendars, 1939-1943 (Box 90)
  - Printed material (Box 91)
    - Murphy-personal (Box 91)
    - Philippine Islands (Box 92)
    - Philippine Islands (Box 93)
    - President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement (Box 94)
    - Attorney General Reports (Box 94)
    - Miscellaneous Supreme Court briefs (Box 94)
- Audio-Visual Materials
  Visual Materials: photographs, films, drawings, and newspaper cartoons, ca. 1900-1949 (Boxes 95-98, and Ac and UAl oversize folders). This series was not included in the microfilm project.
  - Photographs
    - Portraits, 2 folders (Box 95)
    - Youth (Box 95)
    - World War, 1914-1918 (Box 95)
    - Mayor, 1930-May 1933; 4 folders (Box 95)
    - Governor-General, Philippine Islands, 3 folders (Box 95)
    - Governor-General, Philippine Islands (Malacanang Palace), 1934 (Box 95)
    - F.D.R. and Frank Murphy, 1936 (Box 95)
    - Governor of Michigan, 1936-1939; 2 folders (Box 95)
    - Attorney General of the U.S. (Box 95)
    - World War, 1939-1945 (Box 95)
    - Justice, U.S. Supreme Court (Box 95)
    - Funeral (Box 95)
    - Family, 2 folders (Box 95)
    - Women (Reel 95)
    - Harbor Beach, Michigan (Box 96)
    - Philippine War Relief of the U.S., Inc.
      - Dental Services (Box 96)
      - Disaster areas (Box 96)
      - Educational programs (Box 96)
      - Facilities (Box 96)
      - Food and clothing (Box 96)
      - Housing (Box 96)
      - Medical care (Box 96)
      - Military operations (Box 96)
      - Miscellaneous (includes Quezon photo) (Box 96)
      - Natives (Box 96)
      - Staff (Box 96)
      - Victims and casualties of war (Box 96)
    - Buildings (Box 96)
    - Museum (Box 96)
    - Postcards-European scenes (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous or unidentified, 2 folders (Box 96)
  - Negatives
    - Children and hospitals (Box 96)
    - Malacanang Palace (Box 96)
    - Outdoors (Box 96)
    - Riding (Box 96)
    - War photos (Box 96)
  - Drawings and cartoons
    - Miscellaneous (Box 96)
  - Motion pictures
    (In 1986 certain films were transferred onto VHS cassettes; reel numbers are indicated.)
    - "Glimpse of Tokyo" [1], 1932; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes. (Box 97)
    - Untitled [In the Philippines] [2] [VHS Cassette 1], undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Includes Frank Murphy, family, and staff, as well as scenes of Philippine life.)
    - "Inauguration of President Manuel Quezon" [Reel 1] [3] [VHS Cassettel 2] black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes., November 15, 1935 (Box 97)
      (Includes footage of Murphy, Quezon, Vice-President John Nance Gardner, and Joseph T. Byrns, among others.)
    - Untitled [In the Philippines] [4] [VHS Cassette 1], Undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Includes scenes of Murphy, family, and staff; boats in the harbor, and children.)
    - Untitled [Manila and Baguio Market [5] [VHS Cassette 1], Undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Includes scenes of flood.)
    - "Inauguration of President Manuel Quezon" [Reel 2] [6] [VHS Cassette 2], November 15, 1935; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes scenes of speakers at podium: Murphy, Quezon, etc.)
    - "South Island Inspection Trip" [7] [VHS Cassette 1], Undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes Ed Kenp, Ann Parker (daughter of General Parker), Frank Murphy, and others at Malacanang Palace.)
    - Untitled [In the Philippines] [8] [VHS Reel 1], Undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes reception in the Philippines and a short clip of China(?).)
    - Untitled [9] [VHS Cassette 1], undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes scenes in Hawaii and Manila, taken by Joseph Mills.)
    - Untitled [In the Philippines] [10] [VHS Cassette 2], undated; black & white, silent; 350 ft., approx. 15 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes Murphy trip to southern Island.)
    - Untitled [Settlement of the auto strike] [11], 1937; black & white, sound; 100 ft., approximately 5 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Pathe News Service film of Frank Murphy as Governor of Michigan, at settlement of auto strike, with union and management figures.)
    - Untitled [12], undated; black & white, silent; 50 ft., approximately 2 minutes. Double-exposed film. (Box 97)
    - "Back to Work" [13], 1937; black & white, sound; 50 ft., approximately 2 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Pathe News Service film on settlement of auto strike.)
    - Untitled [In the Philippines] [14] [VHS Cassette 2], undated; black & white, silent; 100 ft., approximately 5 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes footage of harbor and ships.)
    - Untitled [15], 1934; black & white, silent; 100 ft., approximately 5 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes footage of Hong Kong, China.)
    - "Governor Murphy Honored" [16], 1937; black & white, sound; 50 ft., approximately 2 minutes (Box 97)
      (Governor Murphy receives an award from the Irish-American Historical Society.)
    - Untitled [Auto strike] [17], 1937; black & white, silent; 50 ft., approximately 2 minutes (Box 97)
      (Includes footage on auto strike.)
    - Untitled [18], 1934; black & white, silent; 100 ft., approximately 5 minutes. (Box 97)
      (Includes footage of Japan and Hawaii.)
  - Video cassette
    - Copy of newsreel excerpts showing Murphy and A.H. Vandenberg, 1930s (Box 97)
      (includes 7 excerpts)
      - 1. After Felix Frankfurter confirmation hearing excerpt: Frank Murphy explains his handling of sit-down strikers. (Box 97)
      - 2. After excerpt with Secretary of State Cordell Hull signing neutrality proclamation: Frank Murphy tells of drive against foreign agents. (Box 97)
      - 3. Frank Murphy's statement on leaving office as Attorney General to become Supreme Court judge. (Box 97)
      - 4. Frank Murphy sworn in as Attorney General and congratulated by Homer Cummings. (Box 97)
      - 5. Frank Murphy assumes duties as Supreme Court justice. (Box 97)
      - 6. Arthur H. Vandenberg interview at home in Washington, D.C. as potential Republican candidate for President. (Box 97)
      - 7. Howard Hughes at Senate hearing, questioned by Homer Ferguson (Brewster presiding). (Box 97)
  - Sound Recordings
    [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
    - Interview discussing duties and responsibilities of the attorney general of the United States., 1939-05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box SR-3)
      - [Part 1], [86734-SR-1-1]; (Murphy answers a series of questions about the job of Attorney General. Part of series of interviews with cabinet members by Lowell Mellet, broadcast on NBC radio June 6, 1939.)
  - Oversized photographs and other visual material
    - Portraits (Box 98)
    - Informal photos; and Frank Murphy as part of group (Box 98)
    - Portraits of others (Box 98)
    - Political cartoons, 2 folders (Box 98)
    - Political posters; miscellaneous photos (Box 98)
      (see also Campaign poster re Mackinac Bridge November 4, 1938 in Ac oversize folder)
    - Harbor Beach home (Folder UAl)
    - Frank Murphy entering doorway to Harbor Beach office, circa 1945 (Folder UAl)
    - Malacanang Palace, 2 photographs (Folder UAl)
    - Detroit City Hall and other Detroit buildings, 1920s; 3 photographs (Folder UAl)
- Clippings/Scrapbooks
  Clippings/Scrapbooks, 1909-1960 (Rolls 155-165, 42 volumes). The clippings, formerly Boxes 91-95 of the collection were discarded after the completion of microfilming. The scrapbooks were filmed but retained in the original because of the presence of photographic and other visual material. The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically.
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - 1909-June 1933 (Reel 149)
    - July 1933-November 1934 (Reel 150)
    - August 1934-February 1935 (Reel 150)
      (visit of Manuel Quezon to the United States)
    - December 1934-September 1935 (Reel 150)
    - January-October 1935 (Reel 150)
      (Manuel Quezon)
    - October 1935-May 1936 (Reel 150)
    - June 1936-June 1939 (Reel 151)
    - July-December 1939 (Reel 152)
    - 1939 undated (Reel 152)
    - Undated, Justice Department period (Reel 152)
    - Subjects, 1939
      - Gambling and corruption in Michigan (Reel 152)
      - Civil service reform (Reel 152)
      - Conservation (Reel 152)
      - Hospital program (Reel 152)
      - Welfare (Reel 152)
      - Proposed abolition of Highway Commissioner's office (Reel 152)
    - Extracts of news teletype, July 1939-January 1940 (Reel 152)
    - January 1940 (Reel 152)
    - February 1940-April 1948 (Reel 153)
      (include Manila trip clippings and miscellaneous, July 1946, and clippings re Black-Jackson Feud, 1946)
    - May 1948-June 1949 (Reel 154)
    - Murphy obituaries and related stories, July 1949-1962 (Reel 154)
    - Undated (Reel 154)
    - Supreme Court period, undated (Reel 154)
  - Scrapbooks
    - September 5-25, 1930 (Reel 155)
    - September 26-October 14, 1930 (Reel 155)
    - October 15-November 4, 1930 (Reel 155)
    - November 5-December 6, 1930 (Reel 155)
    - December 8, 1930-January 27, 1931 (Reel 155)
    - January 28-March 14, 1931 (Reel 155)
    - March 15-April 18, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - April 19-May 19, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - May 20-June 16, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - June 17-July 8, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - July 9-August 3, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - September 5-28, 1931 (Reel 156)
    - 1931-1933 (Reel 156)
    - April-August 1933 (Reel 157)
    - May-November 1933 (Reel 157)
      (scrapbook compiled by Santiago Artiaga; containing record of a reunion of Michigan alumni in the Philippines on June 15, 1933 in honor of Frank Murphy)
    - September 11-12, 1933 (Reel 157)
      (album relating to a banquet in honor of Governor Murphy in the Philippines)
    - January 10-June 28, 1934 (Reel 157)
    - July 4-December 29, 1934 (Reel 157)
    - January 2-April 22, 1935 (Reel 157)
      (dating through January 22)
    - January 2-April 30, 1935 (Reel 158)
      (dating begins January 23)
    - January 23-June 4, 1935 (Reel 158)
    - May 3-June 27, 1935 (Reel 158)
    - July 3-September 29, 1935 (Reel 158)
    - October 3-November 15, 1935 (Reel 158)
    - November 30, 1935-May 9, 1936 (Reel 158)
    - May 5-June 1936 (Reel 158)
    - June-November 9, 1936 (Reel 158)
      (dating through August 6)
    - June-November 9, 1936 (Reel 159)
      (dating begins August 6)
    - January-July 1937 (Reel 159)
    - July-December 1937 (Reel 159)
    - January-November 1938 (Reel 160)
    - January-June 1939 (Reel 160)
      (July 2 is last date in volume)
    - July 1939-January 1940 (Reel 161)
    - January-December 1940 (Reel 161)
    - January 1941-November 1942 (Reel 161)
    - 1942 (Reel 162)
      (album concerns Frank Murphy's military training at Fort Knox, Kentucky)
    - February 1943-December 1945 (Reel 162)
    - January 1946-April 1949 (Reel 162)
      (dating goes through July 3, 1946)
    - January 1946-April 1949 (Reel 163)
      (dating begins July 1, 1946)
    - 1896-1932 (Reel 163)
      (January 1933 is last date in volume)
    - 1933-1960 (Reel 164)
    - 1946 (Reel 164)
      (album contains special numbers of newspapers and magazines commemorating the inauguration of the Philippine Republic)
    - 1936-1938 (Reel 164)
      (album contains Christmas cards into 1937)
    - 1936-1938 (cont.) (Reel 165)
      (album contains Christmas cards 1937-1938)
    - 1933-1934 (Reel 165)
      (album concerns Marguerite Murphy in the Philippine Islands)
    - February 1935 (Reel 165)
      (photograph album was presented by the Detroit Times as a souvenir of Frank Murphy's first visit home from the Philippine Islands)